<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3Dmath%2F0506391%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=math/0506391&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/6FHZt6qweip22Jye2aZZPjMNcQw</id>
  <updated>2013-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/math/0506391v2</id>
    <updated>2006-09-27T17:41:06Z</updated>
    <published>2005-06-20T09:51:26Z</published>
    <title>Relative Beilinson Monad and Direct Image for Families of Coherent
  Sheaves</title>
    <summary>  The higher direct image complex of a coherent sheaf (or finite complex of
coherent sheaves) under a projective morphism is a fundamental construction
that can be defined via a Cech complex or an injective resolution, both
inherently infinite constructions. Using exterior algebras and relative
versions of theorems of Beilinson and Bernstein-Gel'fand-Gel'fand, we give an
alternate description in finite terms. Using this description we can
characterize the generic complex, over the variety of finite free complexes of
a given shape, as the direct image of an easily-described vector bundle. We can
also give explicit descriptions of the loci in the base spaces of flat families
of sheaves in which some cohomological conditions are satisfied--for example,
the loci where vector bundles on projective space split in a certain way, or
the loci where a projective morphism has higher dimensional fibers. Our
approach is so explicit that it yields an algorithm suited for computer algebra
systems.
  This new version uses relative projectives to give smaller direct image
complexes in many cases. It also includes many small clarifications.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>David Eisenbud</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Frank-Olaf Schreyer</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">42 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/math/0506391v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/math/0506391v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="14F05; 14Q99" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
