<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3Dmath%2F0409114%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=math/0409114&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/3cwZg4ojtsAvp/oDzwWJTbZJYBo</id>
  <updated>2013-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/math/0409114v1</id>
    <updated>2004-09-07T21:19:08Z</updated>
    <published>2004-09-07T21:19:08Z</published>
    <title>Some Geometric Results arising from the Borel Fixed Property</title>
    <summary>  In this paper, we will give some geometric results using generic initial
ideals for the degree reverse lex order. The first application is to the
regularity of a Cohen-Macaulay algebra, and we improve a well-known bound. The
main goal of the paper, though, is to improve on results of Bigatti, Geramita
and Migliore concerning geometric consequences of maximal growth of the Hilbert
function of the Artinian reduction of a set of points. When the points have the
Uniform Position Property, the consequences they gave are even more striking.
Here we weaken the growth condition, assuming only that the values of the
Hilbert function of the Artinian reduction are equal in two consecutive
degrees, and that the first of these degrees is greater than the second
reduction number of the points. We continue to get nice geometric consequences
even from this weaker assumption. However, we have surprising examples to show
that imposing the Uniform Position Property on the points does not give the
striking consequences that one might expect. This leads to a better
understanding of the Hilbert function, and the ideal itself, of a set of points
with the Uniform Position Property, which is an important open question. In the
last section we describe the role played by the Weak Lefschetz Property (WLP)
in this theory, and we show that the general hyperplane section of a smooth
curve may fail to have WLP.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jeaman Ahn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juan C. Migliore</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">31 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/math/0409114v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/math/0409114v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="13D40; 14M05; 13C05; 13P10" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
