<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3Dcs%2F0701037%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=cs/0701037&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/YAsjJrdIwIYEPJLnJLoSXsXSlJk</id>
  <updated>2013-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/cs/0701037v3</id>
    <updated>2009-02-24T18:13:25Z</updated>
    <published>2007-01-06T11:36:50Z</published>
    <title>DMTCP: Transparent Checkpointing for Cluster Computations and the
  Desktop</title>
    <summary>  DMTCP (Distributed MultiThreaded CheckPointing) is a transparent user-level
checkpointing package for distributed applications. Checkpointing and restart
is demonstrated for a wide range of over 20 well known applications, including
MATLAB, Python, TightVNC, MPICH2, OpenMPI, and runCMS. RunCMS runs as a 680 MB
image in memory that includes 540 dynamic libraries, and is used for the CMS
experiment of the Large Hadron Collider at CERN. DMTCP transparently
checkpoints general cluster computations consisting of many nodes, processes,
and threads; as well as typical desktop applications. On 128 distributed cores
(32 nodes), checkpoint and restart times are typically 2 seconds, with
negligible run-time overhead. Typical checkpoint times are reduced to 0.2
seconds when using forked checkpointing. Experimental results show that
checkpoint time remains nearly constant as the number of nodes increases on a
medium-size cluster.
  DMTCP automatically accounts for fork, exec, ssh, mutexes/semaphores, TCP/IP
sockets, UNIX domain sockets, pipes, ptys (pseudo-terminals), terminal modes,
ownership of controlling terminals, signal handlers, open file descriptors,
shared open file descriptors, I/O (including the readline library), shared
memory (via mmap), parent-child process relationships, pid virtualization, and
other operating system artifacts. By emphasizing an unprivileged, user-space
approach, compatibility is maintained across Linux kernels from 2.6.9 through
the current 2.6.28. Since DMTCP is unprivileged and does not require special
kernel modules or kernel patches, DMTCP can be incorporated and distributed as
a checkpoint-restart module within some larger package.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jason Ansel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kapil Arya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gene Cooperman</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17 pages; 2 figures, 8 plots, and 2 tables; description of DMTCP;
  Version 3: describing checkpointing both for distributed multi-threaded
  applications (including MPI), and interactive shell-like languages on
  desktop; Revised to reflect version published in IPDPS-09; Software at:
  http://dmtcp.sourceforge.net/</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/cs/0701037v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/cs/0701037v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.OS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="D.4.5" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
