<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3Dgr-qc%2F0112059%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=gr-qc/0112059&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/5HbCzIGXBsoLBg2lf1TOq7HQN+4</id>
  <updated>2013-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/gr-qc/0112059v2</id>
    <updated>2002-06-20T19:51:12Z</updated>
    <published>2001-12-22T11:22:46Z</published>
    <title>Algebraic approach to time-delay data analysis for LISA</title>
    <summary>  Cancellation of laser frequency noise in interferometers is crucial for
attaining the requisite sensitivity of the triangular 3-spacecraft LISA
configuration. Raw laser noise is several orders of magnitude above the other
noises and thus it is essential to bring it down to the level of other noises
such as shot, acceleration, etc. Since it is impossible to maintain equal
distances between spacecrafts, laser noise cancellation must be achieved by
appropriately combining the six beams with appropriate time-delays. It has been
shown in several recent papers that such combinations are possible. In this
paper, we present a rigorous and systematic formalism based on algebraic
geometrical methods involving computational commutative algebra, which
generates in principle {\it all} the data combinations cancelling the laser
frequency noise. The relevant data combinations form the first module of
syzygies, as it is called in the literature of algebraic geometry. The module
is over a polynomial ring in three variables, the three variables corresponding
to the three time-delays around the LISA triangle. Specifically, we list
several sets of generators for the module whose linear combinations with
polynomial coefficients generate the entire module. We find that this formalism
can also be extended in a straight forward way to cancel Doppler shifts due to
optical bench motions. The two modules are infact isomorphic.
  We use our formalism to obtain the transfer functions for the six beams and
for the generators. We specifically investigate monochromatic gravitational
wave sources in the LISA band and carry out the maximisiation over linear
combinations of the generators of the signal-to-noise ratios with the frequency
and source direction angles as parameters.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>S. V. Dhurandhar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Rajesh Nayak</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J-Y. Vinet</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1103/PhysRevD.65.102002</arxiv:doi>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">27 Pages, 6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Phys.Rev. D70 (2004) 102003</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/gr-qc/0112059v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/gr-qc/0112059v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevD.65.102002" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
