<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1905.11047%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1905.11047&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/PpAF+i8EUxYzTfQ6e5w/A1HWNi8</id>
  <updated>2019-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1905.11047v1</id>
    <updated>2019-05-27T08:52:14Z</updated>
    <published>2019-05-27T08:52:14Z</published>
    <title>Hilbert Series and Plethystics: Paving the path towards 2HDM- and
  MLRSM-EFT</title>
    <summary>  Effective Field Theory technique is one of the most elegant ways to capture
the impact of high scale theory, if any, at some low energy by incorporating
higher mass dimensional ($\geq 5$) effective operators ($\mathcal{O}_i$). The
low energy EFT is described in terms of only light degrees of freedom which can
appear on-shell. An essential task while developing the EFT framework is to
compute these $\mathcal{O}_i$'s. Hilbert Series is a novel and mathematically
robust method to construct the complete set of gauge invariant independent,
effective operators. The HS requires the knowledge of the transformation
properties of the light DOF and the covariant derivatives under the internal
gauge symmetries and conformal groups. The Hilbert Series method, by its
virtue, automatically takes care of the redundancies in the operator set due to
the Equations of Motion of fields and Integration by Parts with impeccable
accuracy. In this paper, we have adopted this methodology to construct the
complete set of independent operators up to dimension-6 in the ``Warsaw"-like
basis for two different Beyond Standard Model scenarios -- 2HDM and MLRSM. For
both these cases, we have calculated the corrections to the scalar, gauge boson
and fermion mass spectra due to the dimension-6 operators. The additional
contributions to all the Feynman vertices are computed and their impact on
different observables, namely Weak mixing angle, Fermi constant, $\rho$ and
oblique parameters. We have further discussed how the magnetic moments of
charged leptons and production and decay of the massive BSM particles, e.g.,
charged scalar and different rare processes are affected in the presence of
effective operators. We have also constructed the effective scalar four-point
interactions and commented on the possible reinvestigation of the theoretical
constraints, e.g., unitarity and vacuum stability within these frameworks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name> Anisha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Supratim Das Bakshi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joydeep Chakrabortty</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Suraj Prakash</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">120 pages, 14 figures, 50 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1905.11047v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1905.11047v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
