<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1807.03766%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1807.03766&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/dyLWPO1IaK259QrikGXwD/a3xQc</id>
  <updated>2018-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1807.03766v1</id>
    <updated>2018-07-10T17:28:16Z</updated>
    <published>2018-07-10T17:28:16Z</published>
    <title>Nilpotence varieties</title>
    <summary>  We consider algebraic varieties canonically associated to any Lie
superalgebra, and study them in detail for super-Poincar\'e algebras of
physical interest. They are the locus of nilpotent elements in (the
projectivized parity reversal of) the odd part of the algebra. Most of these
varieties have appeared in various guises in previous literature, but we study
them systematically here, from a new perspective: as the natural moduli spaces
parameterizing twists of a super-Poincar\'e-invariant physical theory. We
obtain a classification of all possible twists, as well as a systematic
analysis of unbroken symmetry in twisted theories. The natural stratification
of the varieties, the identification of strata with twists, and the action of
Lorentz and $R$-symmetry on the varieties are emphasized. We also include a
short and unconventional exposition of the pure-spinor superfield formalism,
from the perspective of twisting, and demonstrate that it can be applied to
construct familiar multiplets in four-dimensional minimally supersymmetric
theories; in all dimensions and with any amount of supersymmetry, this
technique produces BRST or BV complexes of supersymmetric theories from the
Koszul complex of the cone point over the coordinate ring of the nilpotence
variety, possibly tensored with a module over that coordinate ring. In
addition, we remark on a natural emergence of nilpotence varieties in the
Chevalley-Eilenberg cohomology of supertranslations, and give two applications
related to these ideas: a calculation of Chevalley-Eilenberg cohomology for the
six-dimensional $\mathcal{N}=(2,0)$ supertranslation algebra, and a BV complex
matching the field content of type IIB supergravity from the coordinate ring of
the corresponding nilpotence variety.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Eager</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ingmar Saberi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johannes Walcher</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">66 pages, two figures, two tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1807.03766v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1807.03766v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.RT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="81T60, 17B08, 17B81, 14D21" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
