<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1809.01377%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1809.01377&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/XEAeahYvZlDPFAUNGEfo8Pmtuto</id>
  <updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1809.01377v1</id>
    <updated>2018-09-05T08:22:10Z</updated>
    <published>2018-09-05T08:22:10Z</published>
    <title>The Lecture Hall Cone as a toric deformation</title>
    <summary>  The Lecture Hall cone is a simplicial cone whose lattice points naturally
correspond to Lecture Hall partitions. The celebrated Lecture Hall Theorem of
Bousquet-M\'elou and Eriksson states that a particular specialization of its
multivariate Ehrhart series factors in a very nice and unexpected way. Over the
years, several proofs of this result have been found, but it is still not
considered to be well-understood from a geometric perspective. In this note we
propose two conjectures which aim at clarifying this result. Our main
conjecture is that the Ehrhart ring of the Lecture Hall cone is actually an
initial subalgebra $A_n$ of a certain subalgebra of a polynomial ring, which is
itself isomorphic to a polynomial ring. As passing to initial subalgebras does
not affect the Hilbert function, this explains the observed factorization. We
give a recursive definition of certain Laurent polynomials, which generate the
algebra $A_n$. Our second conjecture is that these Laurent polynomials are in
fact polynomials. We computationally verified that both conjectures hold for
Lecture Hall partitions of length at most 12.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lukas Katthän</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10 pages, To appear in the proceedings of the 2018 Summer Workshop on
  Lattice Polytopes at Osaka University</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1809.01377v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1809.01377v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="Primary: 05A19, Secondary: 05A17, 11C20, 13P10" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
