<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1408.2721%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1408.2721&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/t8h/lEM9rjCKPxj7mN+a3hEZhjA</id>
  <updated>2014-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1408.2721v1</id>
    <updated>2014-08-12T14:18:37Z</updated>
    <published>2014-08-12T14:18:37Z</published>
    <title>Certifying solutions to overdetermined and singular polynomial systems
  over Q</title>
    <summary>  This paper is concerned with certifying that a given point is near an exact
root of an overdetermined or singular polynomial system with rational
coefficients. The difficulty lies in the fact that consistency of
overdetermined systems is not a continuous property. Our certification is based
on hybrid symbolic-numeric methods to compute the exact "rational univariate
representation" (RUR) of a component of the input system from approximate
roots. For overdetermined polynomial systems with simple roots, we compute an
initial RUR from approximate roots. The accuracy of the RUR is increased via
Newton iterations until the exact RUR is found, which we certify using exact
arithmetic. Since the RUR is well-constrained, we can use it to certify the
given approximate roots using alpha-theory. To certify isolated singular roots,
we use a determinantal form of the "isosingular deflation", which adds new
polynomials to the original system without introducing new variables. The
resulting polynomial system is overdetermined, but the roots are now simple,
thereby reducing the problem to the overdetermined case. We prove that our
algorithms have complexity that are polynomial in the input plus the output
size upon successful convergence, and we use worst case upper bounds for
termination when our iteration does not converge to an exact RUR. Examples are
included to demonstrate the approach.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulay Ayyildiz Akoglu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan D. Hauenstein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Agnes Szanto</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1408.2721v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1408.2721v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
