<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1903.02617%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1903.02617&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/9bmVs5Km1rpjKBRACiQr+3cphwc</id>
  <updated>2019-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.02617v1</id>
    <updated>2019-03-06T21:20:33Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-06T21:20:33Z</published>
    <title>Oscillations and bistability in a model of ERK regulation</title>
    <summary>  This work concerns the question of how two important dynamical properties,
oscillations and bistability, emerge in an important biological signaling
network. Specifically, we consider a model for dual-site phosphorylation and
dephosphorylation of extracellular signal-regulated kinase (ERK). We prove that
oscillations persist even as the model is greatly simplified (reactions are
made irreversible and intermediates are removed). Bistability, however, is much
less robust -- this property is lost when intermediates are removed or even
when all reactions are made irreversible. Moreover, bistability is
characterized by the presence of two reversible, catalytic reactions: as other
reactions are made irreversible, bistability persists as long as one or both of
the specified reactions is preserved. Finally, we investigate the maximum
number of steady states, aided by a network's "mixed volume" (a concept from
convex geometry). Taken together, our results shed light on the question of how
oscillations and bistability emerge from a limiting network of the ERK network
-- namely, the fully processive dual-site network -- which is known to be
globally stable and therefore lack both oscillations and bistability. Our
proofs are enabled by a Hopf bifurcation criterion due to Yang, analyses of
Newton polytopes arising from Hurwitz determinants, and recent
characterizations of multistationarity for networks having a steady-state
parametrization.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nida Obatake</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anne Shiu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaoxian Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Angelica Torres</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">33 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables, 3 appendices</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.02617v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1903.02617v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.MN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.MN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.DS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
