<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1912.02138%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1912.02138&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/lYvGvx3pFwtleN3OVre0vM3mrI8</id>
  <updated>2020-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.02138v1</id>
    <updated>2019-12-04T17:41:11Z</updated>
    <published>2019-12-04T17:41:11Z</published>
    <title>Distance to the stochastic part of phylogenetic varieties</title>
    <summary>  Modelling the substitution of nucleotides along a phylogenetic tree is
usually done by a hidden Markov process. This allows to define a distribution
of characters at the leaves of the trees and one might be able to obtain
polynomial relationships among the probabilities of different characters. The
study of these polynomials and the geometry of the algebraic varieties that
define can be used to reconstruct phylogenetic trees. However, not all points
in these algebraic varieties have biological sense. In this paper, we explore
the extent to which adding semialgebraic conditions arising from the
restriction to parameters with statistical meaning can improve existing methods
of phylogenetic reconstruction. To this end, our aim is to compute the distance
of data points to algebraic varieties and to the stochastic part of theses
varieties. Computing these distances involves optimization by nonlinear
programming algorithms. We use analytical methods to find some of these
distances for quartet trees evolving under the Kimura 3-parameter or the
Jukes-Cantor models. Numerical algebraic geometry and computational algebra
play also a fundamental role in this paper.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Marta Casanellas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jesús Fernández-Sánchez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marina Garrote-López</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">27 pages; 8 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.02138v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1912.02138v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
