<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1802.08860%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1802.08860&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/7dfXBgXDrQ6q36VwpS0h/Q+c9jQ</id>
  <updated>2018-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1802.08860v1</id>
    <updated>2018-02-24T15:11:33Z</updated>
    <published>2018-02-24T15:11:33Z</published>
    <title>Cohomologies of coherent sheaves and massless spectra in F-theory</title>
    <summary>  In this PhD thesis we investigate the significance of Chow groups for zero
mode counting and anomaly cancellation in F-theory vacua.
  The major part of this thesis focuses on zero mode counting. We explain that
elements of Chow group describe a subset of gauge backgrounds and give rise to
a line bundle on each matter curve. The sheaf cohomologies of these line
bundles are found to encode the chiral and anti-chiral localised zero modes in
this compactification. Therefore, it is of prime interest to compute these
sheaf cohomologies. Unfortunately, the line bundles in question are in general
non-pullback line bundles. In particular, this is the case for the hypercharge
flux employed in F-theory models of grand unified theories (GUTs).
Consequently, existing methods, such as the cohomCalg-algorithm, cannot be
applied. In collaboration with the mathematician Mohamed Barakat, we have
therefore implemented algorithms which determine the sheaf cohomologies of all
coherent sheaves on toric varieties. These algorithms are provided by the
gap-package SheafCohomologiesOnToricVarieties which extends the homalg-project
of Mohamed Barakat. We exemplify these algorithms in explicit (toy-)models of
F-theory GUTs.
  As a spin-off of this analysis, we proved that in an entire class of F-theory
vacua, the matter surface fluxes satisfy a number of relations in the Chow
ring, which we related to anomaly cancellation. Based on this evidence we
conjecture that the well-known anomaly cancellation conditions in F-theory -
typically phrased as intersections in the cohomology ring - can be extended
even to relations in the Chow ring.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Bies</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">PhD thesis</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1802.08860v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1802.08860v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
