<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1809.06758%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1809.06758&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/mfwzICnWRu+yZ6txat0BSizVpYQ</id>
  <updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1809.06758v1</id>
    <updated>2018-09-18T14:17:30Z</updated>
    <published>2018-09-18T14:17:30Z</published>
    <title>State-Dependent Kernel Selection for Conditional Sampling of Graphs</title>
    <summary>  This paper introduces new efficient algorithms for two problems: sampling
conditional on vertex degrees in unweighted graphs, and sampling conditional on
vertex strengths in weighted graphs. The algorithms can sample conditional on
the presence or absence of an arbitrary number of edges. The resulting
conditional distributions provide the basis for exact tests. Existing samplers
based on MCMC or sequential importance sampling are generally not scalable;
their efficiency degrades in sparse graphs. MCMC methods usually require
explicit computation of a Markov basis to navigate the complex state space;
this is computationally intensive even for small graphs. We use state-dependent
kernel selection to develop new MCMC samplers. These do not require a Markov
basis, and are efficient both in sparse and dense graphs. The key idea is to
intelligently select a Markov kernel on the basis of the current state of the
chain. We apply our methods to testing hypotheses on a real network and
contingency table. The algorithms appear orders of magnitude more efficient
than existing methods in the test cases considered.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>James Scott</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Axel Gandy</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Package implementing the samplers can be found at
  https://github.com/jscott6/cgsampr</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1809.06758v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1809.06758v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
