<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1808.09727%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1808.09727&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/tkUJJyBS8GGyI7IT276QRbQeBMA</id>
  <updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1808.09727v1</id>
    <updated>2018-08-29T11:08:14Z</updated>
    <published>2018-08-29T11:08:14Z</published>
    <title>Towards Massively Parallel Computations in Algebraic Geometry</title>
    <summary>  Introducing parallelism and exploring its use is still a fundamental
challenge for the computer algebra community. In high performance numerical
simulation, on the other hand, transparent environments for distributed
computing which follow the principle of separating coordination and computation
have been a success story for many years. In this paper, we explore the
potential of using this principle in the context of computer algebra. More
precisely, we combine two well-established systems: The mathematics we are
interested in is implemented in the computer algebra system Singular, whose
focus is on polynomial computations, while the coordination is left to the
workflow management system GPI-Space, which relies on Petri nets as its
mathematical modeling language, and has been successfully used for coordinating
the parallel execution (autoparallelization) of academic codes as well as for
commercial software in application areas such as seismic data processing. The
result of our efforts is a major step towards a framework for massively
parallel computations in the application areas of Singular, specifically in
commutative algebra and algebraic geometry. As a first test case for this
framework, we have modeled and implemented a hybrid smoothness test for
algebraic varieties which combines ideas from Hironaka's celebrated
desingularization proof with the classical Jacobian criterion. Applying our
implementation to two examples originating from current research in algebraic
geometry, one of which cannot be handled by other means, we illustrate the
behavior of the smoothness test within our framework, and investigate how the
computations scale up to 256 cores.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Janko Boehm</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wolfram Decker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anne Frühbis-Krüger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Franz-Josef Pfreundt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mirko Rahn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lukas Ristau</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">39 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1808.09727v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1808.09727v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="68W10 (Primary), 68W30, 14B05, 14Q99 (Secondary)" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
