<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1606.03098%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1606.03098&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/nhLqQAmeN+9PsdWRRg4VK20Oh9o</id>
  <updated>2016-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1606.03098v2</id>
    <updated>2016-07-27T07:12:55Z</updated>
    <published>2016-06-09T20:00:11Z</published>
    <title>The Segre zeta function of an ideal</title>
    <summary>  We define a power series associated with a homogeneous ideal in a polynomial
ring, encoding information on the Segre classes defined by extensions of the
ideal in projective spaces of arbitrarily high dimension. We prove that this
power series is rational, with poles corresponding to generators of the ideal,
and with numerator of bounded degree and with nonnegative coefficients. We also
prove that this `Segre zeta function' only depends on the integral closure of
the ideal.
  The results follow from good functoriality properties of the `shadows' of
rational equivalence classes of projective bundles. More precise results can be
given if all homogeneous generators have the same degree, and for monomial
ideals.
  In certain cases, the general description of the Segre zeta function given
here leads to substantial improvements in the speed of algorithms for the
computation of Segre classes. We also compute the projective ranks of a
nonsingular variety in terms of the corresponding zeta function, and we discuss
the Segre zeta function of a local complete intersection of low codimension in
projective space.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paolo Aluffi</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1606.03098v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1606.03098v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="14C17" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
