<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1202.4384%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1202.4384&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/9JA//HzOyDwiaAnsgq+g0Wj0pG0</id>
  <updated>2013-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1202.4384v1</id>
    <updated>2012-02-20T17:05:30Z</updated>
    <published>2012-02-20T17:05:30Z</published>
    <title>Computable Hilbert Schemes</title>
    <summary>  In this PhD thesis we propose an algorithmic approach to the study of the
Hilbert scheme. Developing algorithmic methods, we also obtain general results
about Hilbert schemes. In Chapter 1 we discuss the equations defining the
Hilbert scheme as subscheme of a suitable Grassmannian and in Chapter 5 we
determine a new set of equations of degree lower than the degree of equations
known so far. In Chapter 2 we study the most important objects used to project
algorithmic techniques, namely Borel-fixed ideals. We determine an algorithm
computing all the saturated Borel-fixed ideals with Hilbert polynomial assigned
and we investigate their combinatorial properties. In Chapter 3 we show a new
type of flat deformations of Borel-fixed ideals which lead us to give a new
proof of the connectedness of the Hilbert scheme. In Chapter 4 we construct
families of ideals that generalize the notion of family of ideals sharing the
same initial ideal with respect to a fixed term ordering. Some of these
families correspond to open subsets of the Hilbert scheme and can be used to a
local study of the Hilbert scheme. In Chapter 6 we deal with the problem of the
connectedness of the Hilbert scheme of locally Cohen-Macaulay curves in the
projective 3-space. We show that one of the Hilbert scheme considered a "good"
candidate to be non-connected, is instead connected. Moreover there are three
appendices that present and explain how to use the implementations of the
algorithms proposed.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paolo Lella</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">This is the PhD thesis of the author. Most of the results appeared or
  are going to appear in some paper. However the thesis contains more detailed
  explanations, proofs and remarks and it can be used also as handbook for all
  algorithms proposed and available at
  http://www.personalweb.unito.it/paolo.lella/HSC/index.html . arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1101.2866 by other authors</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1202.4384v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1202.4384v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.MS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="14C05, 13P10, 13P99, 15A75, 13C99, 14Q20, 14H50, 14Q05" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
