<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1402.0490%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1402.0490&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/mkHOOtiDYoMI4eRO1v6nX2XadQo</id>
  <updated>2014-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1402.0490v1</id>
    <updated>2014-02-03T20:45:46Z</updated>
    <published>2014-02-03T20:45:46Z</published>
    <title>Legendrian knots and constructible sheaves</title>
    <summary>  We study the unwrapped Fukaya category of Lagrangian branes ending on a
Legendrian knot. Our knots live at contact infinity in the cotangent bundle of
a surface, the Fukaya category of which is equivalent to the category of
constructible sheaves on the surface itself. Consequently, our category can be
described as constructible sheaves with singular support controlled by the
front projection of the knot. We use a theorem of Guillermou-Kashiwara-Schapira
to show that the resulting category is invariant under Legendrian isotopies,
and conjecture it is equivalent to the representation category of the
Chekanov-Eliashberg differential graded algebra.
  We also find two connections to topological knot theory. First, drawing a
positive braid closure on the annulus, the moduli space of rank-n objects maps
to the space of local systems on a circle. The second page of the spectral
sequence associated to the weight filtration on the pushforward of the constant
sheaf is the (colored-by-n) triply-graded Khovanov-Rozansky homology. Second,
drawing a positive braid closure in the plane, the number of points of our
moduli spaces over a finite field with q elements recovers the lowest
coefficient in 'a' of the HOMFLY polynomial of the braid closure. This last
statement leads us to conjecture that when the braid closure is the link of a
singular plane curve, our moduli space is the corresponding wild character
variety.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Vivek Shende</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Treumann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Zaslow</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">77 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1402.0490v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1402.0490v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.SG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.SG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.GT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
