<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1904.02123%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1904.02123&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/s8bpdwP40EZsjY6jvwTO9pFgoyM</id>
  <updated>2019-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1904.02123v1</id>
    <updated>2019-04-03T17:36:59Z</updated>
    <published>2019-04-03T17:36:59Z</published>
    <title>Projective geometry of Wachspress coordinates</title>
    <summary>  We show that there is a unique hypersurface of minimal degree passing through
the non-faces of a polytope which is defined by a simple hyperplane
arrangement. This generalizes the construction of the adjoint curve of a
polygon by Wachspress in 1975. The defining polynomial of our adjoint
hypersurface is the adjoint polynomial introduced by Warren in 1996. This is a
key ingredient for the definition of Wachspress coordinates, which are
barycentric coordinates on an arbitrary convex polytope. We describe the
Wachspress map, the rational map defined by the Wachspress coordinates, and the
Wachspress variety, the image of this map. The inverse of the Wachspress map is
the projection from the linear span of the image of the adjoint hypersurface.
To relate adjoints of polytopes to classical adjoints of divisors in algebraic
geometry, we study irreducible hypersurfaces that have the same degree and
multiplicity along the non-faces of a polytope as its defining hyperplane
arrangement. We list all finitely many combinatorial types of polytopes in
dimensions two and three for which such irreducible hypersurfaces exist. In the
case of polygons, the general such curves are elliptic. In the
three-dimensional case, the general such surfaces are either K3 or elliptic.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kathlén Kohn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kristian Ranestad</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1904.02123v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1904.02123v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="14N20, 14N30, 52B10, 52B11, 14J70, 14J28, 14J27, 14J32" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
