<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1108.1201%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1108.1201&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/R7c8D7QyxEYaOoH/HHfX1LToPKk</id>
  <updated>2016-08-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1108.1201v2</id>
    <updated>2011-12-14T20:45:47Z</updated>
    <published>2011-08-04T20:00:05Z</published>
    <title>Numerical Polynomial Homotopy Continuation Method and String Vacua</title>
    <summary>  Finding vacua for the four dimensional effective theories for supergravity
which descend from flux compactifications and analyzing them according to their
stability is one of the central problems in string phenomenology. Except for
some simple toy models, it is, however, difficult to find all the vacua
analytically. Recently developed algorithmic methods based on symbolic computer
algebra can be of great help in the more realistic models. However, they suffer
from serious algorithmic complexities and are limited to small system sizes. In
this article, we review a numerical method called the numerical polynomial
homotopy continuation (NPHC) method, first used in the areas of lattice field
theories, which by construction finds \textit{all} of the vacua of a given
potential that is known to have only isolated solutions. The NPHC method is
known to suffer from no major algorithmic complexities and is
\textit{embarrassingly parallelizable}, and hence its applicability goes way
beyond the existing symbolic methods. We first solve a simple toy model as a
warm up example to demonstrate the NPHC method at work and compare the results
with the available results from the symbolic methods. We then show that all the
vacua of a more complicated model of M theory compactified on the coset
$\frac{SU(3)\times U(1)}{U(1)\times U(1)}$, which has an SU(3) structure, can
be obtained by the NPHC method using a desktop machine in just about one hour,
a feat which was reported to be prohibitively difficult by the existing
symbolic methods. Finally, we compare the various technicalities between the
two methods.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dhagash Mehta</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1155/2011/263937</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2011/263937" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">19 pages. Published in the Special Issue on Computational Algebraic
  Geometry in String and Gauge Theory: Advances in High Energy Physics Volume
  2011 (2011)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1108.1201v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1108.1201v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
