<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1806.10578%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1806.10578&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/USUq3TjZGL8DAH+WHnsLZBvN/YE</id>
  <updated>2018-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1806.10578v1</id>
    <updated>2018-06-27T17:23:45Z</updated>
    <published>2018-06-27T17:23:45Z</published>
    <title>Fiber product homotopy method for multiparameter eigenvalue problems</title>
    <summary>  We develop a new homotopy method for solving multiparameter eigenvalue
problems (MEPs) called the fiber product homotopy method. It requires
deformation of exponentially fewer equations compared to existing homotopy
methods for MEPs. We show that the fiber product homotopy method theoretically
finds all eigenpairs of an MEP with probability one. It is especially
well-suited for singular MEPs, a weakness of all other existing methods, as the
fiber product homotopy method is provably convergent with probability one for
singular problems as well, a fact borne out by numerical experiments. More
generally, our numerical experiments indicate that the fiber product homotopy
method significantly outperforms the standard Delta method in terms of
accuracy, with consistent backward errors on the order of $10^{-16}$ without
any use of extended precision. In terms of speed, it significantly outperforms
previous homotopy-based methods on all problems and outperforms the Delta
method on larger problems, and is also highly parallelizable. We show that the
fiber product MEP that we solve in the fiber product homotopy method, although
mathematically equivalent to a standard MEP, is typically a much
better-conditioned problem.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jose Israel Rodriguez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lek-Heng Lim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yiling You</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">27 pages, 8 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1806.10578v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1806.10578v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="65H20, 65H17, 65H10, 35P30" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
