<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1505.05209%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1505.05209&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/4DgKnxrNwCPYsHCkycDXGiuiKpE</id>
  <updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1505.05209v1</id>
    <updated>2015-05-19T23:26:18Z</updated>
    <published>2015-05-19T23:26:18Z</published>
    <title>Degree bounds for local cohomology</title>
    <summary>  Let R be a non-negatively graded Cohen-Macaulay ring with R_0 a
Cohen-Macaulay factor ring of a local Gorenstein ring. Let d be the dimension
of R, m be the maximal homogeneous ideal of R, and M be a finitely generated
graded R-module.
  It has long been known how to read information about the socle degrees of the
local cohomology module H_m^0(M) from the twists in position d in a resolution
of M by free R-modules. It has also long been known how to use local cohomology
to read valuable information from complexes which approximate resolutions in
the sense that they have positive homology of small Krull dimension. The
present paper reads information about the maximal generator degree (rather than
the socle degree) of H_m^0M from the twists in position d-1 (rather than
position d) in an approximate resolution of M.
  We apply the local cohomology results to draw conclusions about the maximum
generator degree of the second symbolic power of the prime ideal defining a
monomial curve and the second symbolic power of the ideal defining a finite set
of points in projective space.
  There is an application to general hyperplane sections of subschemes of
projective space over an infinite field.
  There is an application of the local cohomology techniques to partial
Castelnuovo-Mumford regularity. There is a further application to the ideals
generated by the lower order Pfaffians of an alternating matrix.
  One additional application to the study of blow-up algebras appears in a
separate paper.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew R. Kustin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Claudia Polini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bernd Ulrich</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1505.05209v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1505.05209v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="13" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
