<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1609.08648%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1609.08648&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/HJJmyjk/q86NIfNCS7YSboJZIqY</id>
  <updated>2017-08-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.08648v1</id>
    <updated>2016-09-27T20:19:41Z</updated>
    <published>2016-09-27T20:19:41Z</published>
    <title>Negative curves on symmetric blowups of the projective plane,
  resurgences and Waldschmidt constants</title>
    <summary>  The Klein and Wiman configurations are highly symmetric configurations of
lines in the projective plane arising from complex reflection groups. One
noteworthy property of these configurations is that all the singularities of
the configuration have multiplicity at least three. In this paper we study the
surface X obtained by blowing up the projective plane in the singular points of
one of these line configurations. We study invariant curves on X in detail,
with a particular emphasis on curves of negative self-intersection. We use the
representation theory of the stabilizers of the singular points to discover
several invariant curves of negative self-intersection on X, and use these
curves to study Nagata-type questions for linear series on X.
  The homogeneous ideal I of the collection of points in the configuration is
an example of an ideal where the symbolic cube of the ideal is not contained in
the square of the ideal; ideals with this property are seemingly quite rare.
The resurgence and asymptotic resurgence are invariants which were introduced
to measure such failures of containment. We use our knowledge of negative
curves on X to compute the resurgence of I exactly. We also compute the
asymptotic resurgence and Waldschmidt constant exactly in the case of the Wiman
configuration of lines, and provide estimates on both for the Klein
configuration.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Bauer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra Di Rocco</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brian Harbourne</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jack Huizenga</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexandra Seceleanu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Szemberg</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">40 pages, comments welcome!</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.08648v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1609.08648v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.RT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="14C20, 14J26, 13A50, 13P10 (Primary), 14J50, 14Q20, 11H46, 52C30,&#10;  32S22 (Secondary)" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
