<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1508.05317%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1508.05317&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/Rfaq3HiXOSG0fO9kKDGoV3NiIyM</id>
  <updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1508.05317v1</id>
    <updated>2015-08-21T15:46:34Z</updated>
    <published>2015-08-21T15:46:34Z</published>
    <title>Identification of control targets of Boolean molecular network models
  via computational algebra</title>
    <summary>  Motivation: Many problems in biomedicine and other areas of the life sciences
can be characterized as control problems, with the goal of finding strategies
to change a disease or otherwise undesirable state of a biological system into
another, more desirable, state through an intervention, such as a drug or other
therapeutic treatment. The identification of such strategies is typically based
on a mathematical model of the process to be altered through targeted control
inputs. This paper focuses on processes at the molecular level that determine
the state of an individual cell, involving signaling or gene regulation. The
mathematical model type considered is that of Boolean networks. The potential
control targets can be represented by a set of nodes and edges that can be
manipulated to produce a desired effect on the system. Experimentally, node
manipulation requires technology to completely repress or fully activate a
particular gene product while edge manipulations only require a drug that
inactivates the interaction between two gene products. Results: This paper
presents a method for the identification of potential intervention targets in
Boolean molecular network models using algebraic techniques. The approach
exploits an algebraic representation of Boolean networks to encode the control
candidates in the network wiring diagram as the solutions of a system of
polynomials equations, and then uses computational algebra techniques to find
such controllers. The control methods in this paper are validated through the
identification of combinatorial interventions in the signaling pathways of
previously reported control targets in two well studied systems, a p53-mdm2
network and a blood T cell lymphocyte granular leukemia survival signaling
network.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>David Murrugarra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alan Veliz-Cuba</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Boris Aguilar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Reinhard Laubenbacher</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 4 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1508.05317v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1508.05317v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.MN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.MN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
