<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1607.07600%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1607.07600&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/MgikHNzpl7nxXrovXZkIGYHorxQ</id>
  <updated>2016-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1607.07600v1</id>
    <updated>2016-07-26T09:14:50Z</updated>
    <published>2016-07-26T09:14:50Z</published>
    <title>An introduction to computational algebraic statistics</title>
    <summary>  In this paper, we introduce the fundamental notion of a Markov basis, which
is one of the first connections between commutative algebra and statistics. The
notion of a Markov basis is first introduced by Diaconis and Sturmfels (1998)
for conditional testing problems on contingency tables by Markov chain Monte
Carlo methods. In this method, we make use of a connected Markov chain over the
given conditional sample space to estimate the P-values numerically for various
conditional tests. A Markov basis plays an importance role in this arguments,
because it guarantees the connectivity of the chain, which is needed for
unbiasedness of the estimate, for arbitrary conditional sample space. As
another important point, a Markov basis is characterized as generators of the
well-specified toric ideals of polynomial rings. This connection between
commutative algebra and statistics is the main result of Diaconis and Sturmfels
(1998). After this first paper, a Markov basis is studied intensively by many
researchers both in commutative algebra and statistics, which yields an
attractive field called computational algebraic statistics. In this paper, we
give a review of the Markov chain Monte Carlo methods for contingency tables
and Markov bases, with some fundamental examples. We also give some
computational examples by algebraic software Macaulay2 and statistical software
R. Readers can also find theoretical details of the problems considered in this
paper and various results on the structure and examples of Markov bases in
Aoki, Hara and Takemura (2012).
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Satoshi Aoki</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Kobe-Lyon Summer School (2015), Lecture Notes, Algorithms and
  Computation in Mathematics, 28 pages, 5 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1607.07600v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1607.07600v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="62H17, 65C05, 65C40, 13F20" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
