<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1705.06568%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1705.06568&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/TGwkRmND5YFZfP+9F5o7vNS35Fc</id>
  <updated>2017-08-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1705.06568v1</id>
    <updated>2017-04-28T04:17:27Z</updated>
    <published>2017-04-28T04:17:27Z</published>
    <title>Locating and counting equilibria of the Kuramoto model with rank one
  coupling</title>
    <summary>  The Kuramoto model describes synchronization behavior among coupled
oscillators and enjoys successful application in a wide variety of fields. Many
of these applications seek phase-coherent solutions, i.e., equilibria of the
model. Historically, research has focused on situations where the number of
oscillators, n, is extremely large and can be treated as being infinite. More
recently, however, applications have arisen in areas such as electrical
engineering with more modest values of n. For these, the equilibria can be
located by solving a system of polynomial equations utilizing techniques from
algebraic geometry. Typical methods for solving such systems locate all complex
solutions even though only the real solutions, corresponding to equilibria of
the model, are of physical interest. In this paper, we develop an algorithm to
locate only all equilibria of the model, thereby shortening computation time by
several orders of magnitude in certain situations. This is accomplished by
choosing specific equilibria representatives and the consequent algebraic
decoupling of the system. We compare this solving approach to other
computational algebraic geometric methods. Furthermore, analyzing this approach
allows us to prove, asymptotically, that the maximum number of equilibria grows
at the same rate as the number of complex solutions of a corresponding
polynomial system. Finally, we conjecture an upper bound on the maximum number
of equilibria for any number of oscillators which generalizes the known cases
and is obtained on a range of explicitly provided natural frequencies.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Owen Coss</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan D. Hauenstein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hoon Hong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel K. Molzahn</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Keywords: Kuramoto model, equilibria, univariate solving, homotopy
  continuation, numerical algebraic geometry</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1705.06568v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1705.06568v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.DS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="65H10, 68W30, 14Q99" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
