<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1606.07160%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1606.07160&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/U3mgTRtZECzriMChPKAAbjhDFg4</id>
  <updated>2016-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1606.07160v1</id>
    <updated>2016-06-23T01:54:55Z</updated>
    <published>2016-06-23T01:54:55Z</published>
    <title>Distinguishing Convergence on Phylogenetic Networks</title>
    <summary>  We compare the phylogenetic tensors for various trees and networks for two,
three and four taxa. If the probability spaces between one tree or network and
another are not identical then there will be phylogenetic tensors that could
have arisen on one but not the other. We call these two trees or networks
distinguishable from each other. We show that for the binary symmetric model
there are no two-taxon trees and networks that are distinguishable from each
other, however there are three-taxon trees and networks that are
distinguishable from each other.
  We compare the time parameters for the phylogenetic tensors for various taxon
label permutations on a given tree or network. If the time parameters on one
taxon label permutation in terms of the other taxon label permutation are all
non-negative then we say that the two taxon label permutations are not network
identifiable from each other. We show that some taxon label permutations are
network identifiable from each other.
  We show that some four-taxon networks satisfy the four-point condition. Of
the two "shapes" of four-taxon rooted trees, one is defined by the cluster,
b,c,d, labelling taxa alphabetically from left to right. The network with this
shape and convergence between the two taxa with the root as their most recent
common ancestor satisfies the four-point condition.
  The phylogenetic tensors contain polynomial equations that cannot be easily
solved for four-taxon or higher trees or networks. We show how methods from
algebraic geometry, such as Gr\"obner bases, can be used to solve the
polynomial equations. We show that some four-taxon trees and networks can be
distinguished from each other.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan Mitchell</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">PhD Thesis</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1606.07160v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1606.07160v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.RT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.QM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
