<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1912.11987%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1912.11987&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/5zrooRmjlNta5WMSnjySJbR2R7g</id>
  <updated>2020-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.11987v1</id>
    <updated>2019-12-15T18:03:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-12-15T18:03:00Z</published>
    <title>Necessary and Sufficient Polynomial Constraints on Compatible Triplets
  of Essential Matrices</title>
    <summary>  The essential matrix incorporates relative rotation and translation
parameters of two calibrated cameras. The well-known algebraic characterization
of essential matrices, i.e. necessary and sufficient conditions under which an
arbitrary matrix (of rank two) becomes essential, consists of a unique matrix
equation of degree three. Based on this equation, a number of efficient
algorithmic solutions to different relative pose estimation problems have been
proposed. In three views, a possible way to describe the geometry of three
calibrated cameras comes from considering compatible triplets of essential
matrices. The compatibility is meant the correspondence of a triplet to a
certain configuration of calibrated cameras. The main goal of this paper is to
give an algebraic characterization of compatible triplets of essential
matrices. Specifically, we propose necessary and sufficient polynomial
constraints on a triplet of real rank-two essential matrices that ensure its
compatibility. The constraints are given in the form of six cubic matrix
equations, one quartic and one sextic scalar equations. An important advantage
of the proposed constraints is their sufficiency even in the case of cameras
with collinear centers. The applications of the constraints may include
relative camera pose estimation in three and more views, averaging of essential
matrices for incremental structure from motion, multiview camera
auto-calibration, etc.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>E. V. Martyushev</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">11 pages, 1 figure</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.11987v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1912.11987v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
