<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1806.02090%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1806.02090&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/cvu9zbdFN87hpl3N8DGpH10jDQk</id>
  <updated>2018-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1806.02090v1</id>
    <updated>2018-06-06T09:41:40Z</updated>
    <published>2018-06-06T09:41:40Z</published>
    <title>Toric degenerations: a bridge between representation theory, tropical
  geometry and cluster algebras</title>
    <summary>  In this thesis we study toric degenerations of projective varieties. We
compare different constructions to understand how and why they are related as s
first step towards developing a global framework. In focus are toric
degenerations obtained from representation theory, tropical geometry and
cluster algebras. Often those rely on valuations and the theory of
Newton-Okounkov bodies. Toric degenerations can be seen as a combinatorial
shadow of the original objects. The goal is therefore to understand why the
different theories are so closely related, by understanding the toric
degenerations they yield first. We choose Grassmannians, flag varieties and
Schubert varieties as starting point as here many different constructions are
applicable. One of our main results gives a sufficient condition for when toric
degenerations obtained using full-rank valuations, independent of how these are
constructed, can be realized using tropical geometry.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lara Bossinger</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">This is a preliminary version of my submitted Phd thesis. Any
  comments are very welcome and greatly appreciated! (136 pages, incl.
  appendices and 36 figures)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1806.02090v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1806.02090v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.RT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
