<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1701.04930%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1701.04930&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/UmLzr/1IMFzT+TbJW2TOhJlYCcI</id>
  <updated>2017-08-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.04930v1</id>
    <updated>2017-01-18T03:05:22Z</updated>
    <published>2017-01-18T03:05:22Z</published>
    <title>Exterior Differential Systems, from Elementary to Advanced</title>
    <summary>  This monograph was developed to support a series of lectures at the Institute
of Mathematics at the Polish Academy of Sciences in September 2016, as part of
a Workshop on the Geometry of Lagrangian Grassmannians and Nonlinear PDEs.
  The goal is to cut the shortest-possible expository path from the common,
elementary concepts of geometry (linear algebra, vector bundles, and algebraic
ideals) to the advanced theorems about the characteristic variety. Hopefully,
these lectures lower the barrier to advanced topics in exterior differential
systems by exposing the audience to elementary versions of several key results
regarding the characteristic variety, and to outline how these results could be
used to push the frontiers of the subject. These key results are:
  1) The incidence correspondence of the characteristic variety, 2) Guillemin
normal form and Quillen's thesis, 3) The Integrability of Characteristics
(Guillemin, Quillen, Sternberg, Gabber), 4) Yang's Hyperbolicity Criterion.
\end{enumerate}
  To accomplish this, the subject of exterior differential systems is
reinterpreted as the study of smooth sub-bundles of the Grassmann bundle over a
smooth manifold. These notes intentionally obscure the role of exterior
differential forms in computation, instead focusing on tableaux as subspaces of
homomorphisms and on symbols as varieties of endomorphisms. Techniques
involving differential ideals or PDE analysis are hardly mentioned. Instead,
Guillemin normal form (a generalization of Jordan decomposition from a single
endomorphism to a variety of endomorphisms) is the primary computational tool.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Abraham D. Smith</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Some proofs here also appeared in an early draft of 1410.7593</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.04930v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1701.04930v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="58A15 (Primary), 35A27, 35A30 (Secondary)" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
