<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D1808.06721%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=1808.06721&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/9wIvKzbQw9iol2/hqT4No31xW7c</id>
  <updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1808.06721v2</id>
    <updated>2018-08-27T20:19:38Z</updated>
    <published>2018-08-20T23:51:27Z</published>
    <title>State Polytopes Related to Two Classes of Combinatorial Neural Codes</title>
    <summary>  Combinatorial neural codes are $0/1$ vectors that are used to model the
co-firing patterns of a set of place cells in the brain. One wide-open problem
in this area is to determine when a given code can be algorithmically drawn in
the plane as a Venn diagram-like figure. A sufficient condition to do so is for
the code to have a property called $k$-inductively pierced. Gross, Obatake, and
Youngs recently used toric algebra to show that a code on three neurons is
$1$-inductively pierced if and only if the toric ideal is trivial or generated
by quadratics. No result is known for additional neurons in the same
generality, part of the difficulty coming from the large number of codewords
possible when additional neurons are used.
  In this article, we study two infinite classes of combinatorial neural codes
in detail. For each code, we explicitly compute its universal Gr\"obner basis.
This is done for the first class by recognizing that the codewords form a
Lawrence-type matrix. With the second class, this is done by showing that the
matrix is totally unimodular. These computations allow one to compute the state
polytopes of the corresponding toric ideals, from which all distinct initial
ideals may be computed efficiently. Moreover, we show that the state polytopes
are combinatorially equivalent to well-known polytopes: the permutohedron and
the stellohedron.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Davis</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">21 pages. Minor typos corrected</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1808.06721v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1808.06721v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
