<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2209.04929%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2209.04929&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SAl2j7behCHKXgtGuyqLRMu5J6o</id>
  <updated>2022-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.04929v1</id>
    <updated>2022-09-11T20:13:09Z</updated>
    <published>2022-09-11T20:13:09Z</published>
    <title>Geometric aspects of the Jacobian of a hyperplane arrangement</title>
    <summary>  We initiate a systematic study of the interactions among algebraic structures
associated to a hyperplane arrangement, namely its module of logarithmic
derivations, formality (in the sense of Falk and Randell), and what we call its
weak perspective representations. Our investigation is inspired by
\textit{Ziegler's pair}, two line arrangements associated to the complete
bipartite graph $K_{3,3}$ which, incidentally, are also known to illustrate the
geometric sensitivity of infinitesimal flexibility in rigidity theory. We
introduce weak perspective representations of hyperplane arrangements to
elucidate these connections. We draw on the rigidity theory literature to
exhibit many examples of line arrangements whose module of logarithmic
derivations is sensitive not just to the intersection lattice but also to the
geometry of the lines. This indicates that rigidity theory may offer a good
place to look for counterexamples to a well-known conjecture of Terao.
  Weak perspective representations are inspired by Whiteley's parallel drawings
from scene analysis. In characteristic zero we show that there is a tight
connection between weak perspective representations of hyperplane arrangements
and polynomials of minimal degree in certain saturations of the Jacobian of the
arrangement. Our approach provides a direct link between formality and the
Jacobian ideal, elucidating and extending prior work of Yuzvinsky.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michael DiPasquale</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jessica Sidman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Will Traves</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">34 pages, 10 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.04929v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2209.04929v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="Primary: 13D02, 14N20, 52C35, Secondary: 52C25" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
