<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2206.14106%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2206.14106&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/ntOI2AOwDodQ0ZFXshdTZCWUQo8</id>
  <updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14106v1</id>
    <updated>2022-06-27T16:51:58Z</updated>
    <published>2022-06-27T16:51:58Z</published>
    <title>Euclidean distance and maximum likelihood retractions by homotopy
  continuation</title>
    <summary>  We define a new second-order retraction map for statistical models. We also
compute retractions using homotopy continuation. Riemannian optimization uses
local methods to solve optimization problems whose constraint set is a smooth
manifold. A linear step along some descent direction usually leaves the
constraint set, and hence retraction maps are used to approximate the
exponential map, and return to the manifold. For many common matrix manifolds,
retraction maps are available, with more or less explicit formulas. For other
implicitly-defined manifolds or varieties, suitable retraction maps are
difficult to compute. We therefore develop Algorithm 1, which uses homotopy
continuation to compute the Euclidean distance retraction for any
implicitly-defined submanifold of $R^n$.
  We also consider statistical models as Riemannian submanifolds of the
probability simplex with the Fisher metric. After defining an analogous maximum
likelihood retraction, Algorithm 2 computes it using homotopy continuation. In
Theorem 2, we prove that the resulting map is a second-order retraction; with
the Levi-Civita connection associated to the Fisher metric, it approximates
geodesics to second-order accuracy.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Heaton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthias Himmelmann</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14106v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2206.14106v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
