<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2107.14721%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2107.14721&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/Ql5MfgogfS4YeDaTxUz9bdJ2Y+4</id>
  <updated>2021-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.14721v2</id>
    <updated>2021-10-25T08:40:05Z</updated>
    <published>2021-07-30T15:52:32Z</published>
    <title>Co-homology of Differential Forms and Feynman diagrams</title>
    <summary>  In the present review we provide an extensive analysis of the intertwinement
between Feynman integrals and cohomology theories in the light of the recent
developments. Feynman integrals enter in several perturbative methods for
solving non linear PDE, starting from Quantum Field Theories and including
General Relativity and Condensed Matter Physics. Precision calculations involve
several loop integrals, one strategy to address which is to bring them back in
terms of linear combinations of a complete set of integrals (the Master
Integrals). In this sense Feynman integrals can be thought as defining a sort
of vector space to be decomposed in term of a basis. Such a task may be simpler
if the vector space is endowed with a scalar product. Recently, it has been
discovered that, interpreting these spaces in terms of twisted cohomology, the
role of a scalar product is played by intersection products. The present review
is meant to provide the mathematical tools, usually familiar to mathematicians
but often not in the standard baggage of physicists, like singular, simplicial
and intersection (co)homologies, hodge structures etc., apt to restate this
strategy on precise mathematical grounds. It is thought to be both an
introduction for beginners interested to the topic, as well as a general
reference providing helpful tools for tackling the several still open problems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sergio Luigi Cacciatori</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maria Conti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simone Trevisan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.3390/universe7090328</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/universe7090328" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">70 pages, 23 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Universe, Volume 7, Issue 9 (September 2021)</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.14721v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2107.14721v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
