<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2003.07382%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2003.07382&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/AztBJFrilophPos8VJOXDjcHWsA</id>
  <updated>2020-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.07382v1</id>
    <updated>2020-03-16T18:05:39Z</updated>
    <published>2020-03-16T18:05:39Z</published>
    <title>Slack Ideals in Macaulay2</title>
    <summary>  Recently Gouveia, Thomas and the authors introduced the slack realization
space, a new model for the realization space of a polytope. It represents each
polytope by its slack matrix, the matrix obtained by evaluating each facet
inequality at each vertex. Unlike the classical model, the slack model
naturally mods out projective transformations. It is inherently algebraic,
arising as the positive part of a variety of a saturated determinantal ideal,
and provides a new computational tool to study classical realizability problems
for polytopes. We introduce the package SlackIdeals for Macaulay2, that
provides methods for creating and manipulating slack matrices and slack ideals
of convex polytopes and matroids. Slack ideals are often difficult to compute.
To improve the power of the slack model, we develop two strategies to simplify
computations: we scale as many entries of the slack matrix as possible to one;
we then obtain a reduced slack model combining the slack variety with the more
compact Grassmannian realization space model. This allows us to study slack
ideals that were previously out of computational reach. As applications, we
show that the well-known Perles polytope does not admit rational realizations
and prove the non-realizability of a large simplicial sphere.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio Macchia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Amy Wiebe</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.07382v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2003.07382v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
