<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2006.14434%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2006.14434&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SD6W4dRA6P1tU5S1ij4s3+KKC5o</id>
  <updated>2020-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.14434v1</id>
    <updated>2020-06-25T14:16:03Z</updated>
    <published>2020-06-25T14:16:03Z</published>
    <title>Resolutions of Initial Ideals of Closed Determinantal Facet Ideals</title>
    <summary>  We study resolutions of initial ideals of closed determinantal facet ideals
with respect to standard lexicographic order. We show that the multigraded
Betti numbers of these ideals are always $0$ or $1$, regardless of the
characteristic of the field. In addition, we show that the standard graded
Betti numbers of closed determinantal facet ideals and their initial ideals
coincide when generators of the ideal come from maximal minors of a generic
$n\times m$ matrix with $n&gt;2$. Next, we give lower bounds on the Betti numbers
of certain classes of ideals of initial terms of the generators of
determinantal facet ideals with respect to arbitrary term orders. We give an
explicit minimal free resolution of the initial ideal of the ideal of maximal
minors with respect to standard lexicographic order. We show that the Betti
numbers of a certain closed determinantal facet ideal and its initial ideal
coincide, verifying a conjecture of Ene, Herzog, and Hibi in a new case. We
give explicit differentials for the linear strand of the initial ideal with
respect to standard lexicographic order of an arbitrary closed determinantal
facet ideal.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayah Almousa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Keller VandeBogert</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">26 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.14434v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2006.14434v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
