<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2002.04818%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2002.04818&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/MRspZbJD+aTYengJGWIlxgcTTD4</id>
  <updated>2020-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.04818v1</id>
    <updated>2020-02-12T06:25:30Z</updated>
    <published>2020-02-12T06:25:30Z</published>
    <title>The apolar algebra of a product of linear forms</title>
    <summary>  Apolarity is an important tool in commutative algebra and algebraic geometry
which studies a form, $f$, by the action of polynomial differential operators
on $f$. The quotient of all polynomial differential operators by those which
annihilate $f$ is called the apolar algebra of $f$. In general, the apolar
algebra of a form is useful for determining its Waring rank, which can be seen
as the problem of decomposing the supersymmetric tensor, associated to the
form, minimally as a sum of rank one supersymmetric tensors. In this article we
study the apolar algebra of a product of linear forms, which generalizes the
case of monomials and connects to the geometry of hyperplane arrangements. In
the first part of the article we provide a bound on the Waring rank of a
product of linear forms under certain genericity assumptions; for this we use
the defining equations of so-called star configurations due to Geramita,
Harbourne, and Migliore. In the second part of the article we use the computer
algebra system Bertini, which operates by homotopy continuation methods, to
solve certain rank equations for catalecticant matrices. Our computations
suggest that, up to a change of variables, there are exactly six homogeneous
polynomials of degree six in three variables which factor completely as a
product of linear forms defining an irreducible multi-arrangement and whose
apolar algebras have dimension six in degree three. As a consequence of these
calculations, we find six cases of such forms with cactus rank six, five of
which also have Waring rank six. Among these are products defining
subarrangements of the braid and Hessian arrangements.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michael DiPasquale</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zachary Flores</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Peterson</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 2 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.04818v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.04818v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="13E10, 13N10, 68W30, 14N20, 15A69" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
