<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2003.02397%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2003.02397&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/9XQQ6oD+ZcJF3/SiZ9yxLHq9dFs</id>
  <updated>2020-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.02397v1</id>
    <updated>2020-03-05T02:03:38Z</updated>
    <published>2020-03-05T02:03:38Z</published>
    <title>Projective Duality, Unexpected Hypersurfaces and Logarithmic Derivations
  of Hyperplane Arrangements</title>
    <summary>  Several papers have been written studying unexpected hypersurfaces. We say a
finite set of points Z admits unexpected hypersurfaces if a general union of
fat linear subspaces imposes less that the expected number of conditions on the
ideal of Z. In this paper, we introduce the concept of a very unexpected
hypersurface. This is a stronger condition which takes into account an
explanation for some hypersurfaces previously considered unexpected. We then
develop a duality theory to relate the study of very unexpected hypersurfaces
to the derivations of dual hyperplane arrangements. This allows us to
generalize results in the plane of Cook, Harbourne, Migliore, Nagel Faenzi, and
Vall\'{e}s to higher dimensions. In particular, we give a criterion to
determine if a set Z admits very unexpected hypersurfaces in the case Z is
invariant under the action of an irreducible reflection group on the ambient
projective space. Our approach has new applications even in the projective
plane where we are able to place strong conditions on sets of points Z which
admit certain types of unexpected curves. We close relating Terao's Freeness
Conjecture for line arrangements to a conjecture due to G. Dirac on
configurations of points in the real plane.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Bill Trok</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">41 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.02397v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2003.02397v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="14N02 (primary) 13A02, 52C02 (secondary)" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
