<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2011.01032%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2011.01032&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/VFlha/1BT4ZbJiKW988c/8aEHcc</id>
  <updated>2021-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.01032v1</id>
    <updated>2020-11-02T15:21:38Z</updated>
    <published>2020-11-02T15:21:38Z</published>
    <title>Semi-regular sequences and other random systems of equations</title>
    <summary>  The security of multivariate cryptosystems and digital signature schemes
relies on the hardness of solving a system of polynomial equations over a
finite field. Polynomial system solving is also currently a bottleneck of
index-calculus algorithms to solve the elliptic and hyperelliptic curve
discrete logarithm problem. The complexity of solving a system of polynomial
equations is closely related to the cost of computing Groebner bases, since
computing the solutions of a polynomial system can be reduced to finding a
lexicographic Groebner basis for the ideal generated by the equations. Several
algorithms for computing such bases exist: We consider those based on repeated
Gaussian elimination of Macaulay matrices. In this paper, we analyze the case
of random systems, where random systems means either semi-regular systems, or
quadratic systems in n variables which contain a regular sequence of n
polynomials. We provide explicit formulae for bounds on the solving degree of
semi-regular systems with m &gt; n equations in n variables, for equations of
arbitrary degrees for m = n+1, and for any m for systems of quadratic or cubic
polynomials. In the appendix, we provide a table of bounds for the solving
degree of semi-regular systems of m = n + k quadratic equations in n variables
for 2 &lt;= k; n &lt;= 100 and online we provide the values of the bounds for 2 &lt;= k;
n &lt;= 500. For quadratic systems which contain a regular sequence of n
polynomials, we argue that the Eisenbud-Green-Harris Conjecture, if true,
provides a sharp bound for their solving degree, which we compute explicitly.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>M. Bigdeli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. De Negri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. M. Dizdarevic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Gorla</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Minko</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Tsakou</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">27 pages, 4 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.01032v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2011.01032v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="Primary: 94A60, 13P10, 13P15, 13P25, Secondary: 13D40" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
