<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2111.06270%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2111.06270&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/YhEMqbwcEJRkVNkjuOLmSZB0h7Q</id>
  <updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.06270v1</id>
    <updated>2021-11-11T15:27:34Z</updated>
    <published>2021-11-11T15:27:34Z</published>
    <title>Quantum Correlations in the Minimal Scenario</title>
    <summary>  In the minimal scenario of quantum correlations, two parties can choose from
two observables with two possible outcomes each. Probabilities are specified by
four marginals and four correlations. The resulting four-dimensional convex
body of correlations, denoted $\mathcal{Q}$, is fundamental for quantum
information theory. It is here studied through the lens of convex algebraic
geometry. We review and systematize what is known and add many details,
visualizations, and complete proofs. A new result is that $\mathcal{Q}$ is
isomorphic to its polar dual. The boundary of $\mathcal{Q}$ consists of
three-dimensional faces isomorphic to elliptopes and sextic algebraic manifolds
of exposed extreme points. These share all basic properties with the usual
maximally CHSH-violating correlations. These patches are separated by cubic
surfaces of non-exposed extreme points. We provide a trigonometric
parametrization of all extreme points, along with their exposing Tsirelson
inequalities and quantum models. All non-classical extreme points (exposed or
not) are self-testing, i.e., realized by an essentially unique quantum model.
  Two principles, which are specific to the minimal scenario, allow a quick and
complete overview: The first is the pushout transformation, the application of
the sine function to each coordinate. This transforms the classical polytope
exactly into the correlation body $\mathcal{Q}$, also identifying the boundary
structures. The second principle, self-duality, reveals the polar dual, i.e.,
the set of all Tsirelson inequalities satisfied by all quantum correlations.
The convex body $\mathcal{Q}$ includes the classical correlations, a cross
polytope, and is contained in the no-signaling body, a 4-cube. These polytopes
are dual to each other, and the linear transformation realizing this duality
also identifies $\mathcal{Q}$ with its dual.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Thinh P. Le</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chiara Meroni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bernd Sturmfels</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Reinhard F. Werner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Timo Ziegler</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.06270v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2111.06270v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
