<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3D%26id_list%3D2011.12578%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=&amp;id_list=2011.12578&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api//Sl9c0xrIZgikXvH/NjMuXq1+Ag</id>
  <updated>2021-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">1</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.12578v1</id>
    <updated>2020-11-25T08:39:41Z</updated>
    <published>2020-11-25T08:39:41Z</published>
    <title>Characteristic Classes of Homogeneous Essential Isolated Determinantal
  Varieties</title>
    <summary>  The (homogeneous) Essentially Isolated Determinantal Variety is the natural
generalization of generic determinantal variety, and is fundamental example to
study non-isolated singularities. In this paper we study the characteristic
classes on these varieties. We give explicit formulas of their
Chern-Schwartz-MacPherson classes via standard Schubert calculus. As
corollaries we obtain formulas for their (generic) sectional Euler
characteristics, characteristic cycles and polar classes. In particular, when
such variety is a hypersurfaces we compute its Milnor class and the Euler
characteristics of the local Milnor fibers. We prove that for such recursive
group orbit hypersurfaces the local Euler obstructions completely determine the
Milnor classes.
  In general for reflective group orbits, on the other hand we propose an
algorithm to compute their local Euler obstructions via the
Chern-Schwartz-MacPherson classes of the orbits, which can be obtained directly
from representation theory. This builds a bridge from representation theory of
the group action to the singularity theory of the induced orbits.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xiping Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Comments are Welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.12578v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2011.12578v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.GT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="14C17, 32S05, 32S50" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
